Syd Hoff Cartoons
Syd Hoff Cartoons
1948-1969
Hoff, Syd, 1912-2004.
2.5 linear ft.
Original drawings by the American cartoonist of Laugh It Off, for King Features Syndicate (1951-1969), and for magazines (1948-1968).
149057
Biographical History
Syd Hoff (1912-2004) was an American humor cartoonist, illustrator and author.
Born September 4, 1912 in New York City, Hoff attended the National Academy of Design and sold his first cartoon to the New Yorker while still in his teens. He became known for his cartoons about tenement and lower-middle-class life in the big city, which ran in the New Yorker. One of his recurring characters, a walrus-mustached man in trousers and undershirt, eventually appeared as the father in a daily strip called Tuffy, done for King Features Syndicate from 1940 to 1950. In 1957 Hoff began a new daily cartoon for King Features titled Laugh It Off which he continued until 1971.
His cartoons have appeared in the New Yorker, Esquire, Look, and other magazines, and he has written and illustrated several children's books including Danny and the Dinosaur. In 1976 he edited and published Editorial and political cartooning: from earliest times to the present, which contains over 700 examples from the works of the world's greatest cartoonists.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Syd Hoff Cartoons consists of original cartoon drawings subdivided by the magazine in which they were published; within each magazine title cartoons are arranged chronologically.
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged alphabetically by the name of the publication in which they appeared (or in the case of Laugh It Off, the publishing organization).
Related Material
has collections of over eighty cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Hoff, Syd, 1912-2004.; Laugh it off (comic strip); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Syd Hoff, 1966, 1968-1970.
Inventory
- Cartoons
  - Escapade, undated; 2 cartoons (Oversize 1)
  - Esquire, 1948; 1951,; 1955,; 1957,; 1958,; undated; 11 cartoons (Oversize 1)
  - King Features Syndicate (Laugh It Off)
    - 1951 (Mar 8), 1953 (Jan 6), 1954 (Jan 16), undated (Box 1)
    - 1953, 1954, undated, 4 cartoons (Oversize 1)
    - 1958-1966, 8 folders; Click here for detailed listing of dates (Box 1)
    - 1967-1969, 3 folders; Click here for detailed listing of dates (Box 2)
  - Look, 1951; 1954,; 1958,; undated; 12 cartoons (Oversize 1)
  - New Yorker, 1958-1959; 1962-1963,; 1966,; undated; 13 cartoons (Oversize 1)
  - Sports Illustrated, Undated (Oversize 1)
  - Suburbia Today, Undated; 1 cartoon (Box 2)
  - Unidentified
    - 1964, 1968, undated, 12 cartoons (Box 2)
    - 1966, "Dancing our Way Through Sixty-Six"; 1 cartoon (Map-case 100)